foreign
[Music]
I haven't done a YouTube in a while so
uh
it's time to do one
as you can see
Christmas Is Here
well it's not here yet but
it is coming soon and I am just packing
up I've got
some camera equipment here
I've got shares I've got water I've got
coffee I've got clothes I got sleeping
bag
I'm gonna be heading out real soon to
hit a ferry
make it over to the mainland Vancouver
and take some photos of
owls
so
without any further ado
time to pack up the Jeep
and uh rush out of here
I can't wait to see what I see and show
you along the way
[Music]
foreign
merry Merry Christmas
to you
good morning everyone I made it
over to the mainland it's the next
morning
I'm just packing up my camera equipment
already some good signs see there's
three big eagles up here
plenty of fields out here with mice and
moles
and the short-eared owls
are
looking for food during the winter
months
it is cooled out
it's not
Frosty at the moment I think it's warmed
up a tiny bit
but I'm out in the marsh
apparently this week is
king tide week so where the ocean
floods this whole area
and high tide is in another hour
I do have rubber boots I didn't bring
them I brought just my hikers they're
waterproof
and I've got my 500 set up to my Nikon
z9
and I'm out
here to see the short-eared owls we've
seen two so far by we there was another
buddy that was here he had to go to work
it's great chatting with him
nice always to have like two set of eyes
and you could stand next to one another
and you can photograph
but the two short-eared owls were way
out there in some of the tall Reeds and
grass and Cocktails and they flew all
the way along kind of the shoreline up
this way
so we were able to kind of pan with it
and one of them went over this way the
other one went back over this way
thing to look out for I guess if you're
out trying to photograph short-eared
owls is that uh they have a shorter tail
so there's a lot of Harrier Hawks
there's like
30 or 40 Harrier Hawks out here and they
got a long tail and they flap quite a
bit so the short-eared owls are easy to
spot because they have such a shorter
tail and they are a little bit slower
with their uh their wingspan
so my
shutter speed is at 1 1600 I might go up
to 2000 or 25 100 to capture some of
their in-flight movements so I make sure
that I have nice tack Sharp Images
and I'm photographing it f 6.3 my ISO
right now is 1600.
is it actually what is my ISO yeah ISO
is 1600
wow so the Ravens are chasing the
short-eared owls kind of harassing them
there are so many like moles and mice
like even right where I am right now
uh you can hear them in the field
squeaking and moving moving around
some of the walls are huge
yeah the tide must have come up and
so that's a good sign that there's
plenty of food
I've got uh some some bars some food
actually in my bag here
and I just gotta watch it because they
will try and get into my bag or
just don't want them chewing through it
or something crazy like that
man it's chilly out
but it's exciting because uh there are a
few short-eared owls they are active
there's so many mice out here that the
worry is that they just you know fill up
on on the mice on the food and then
that's it they're not active at all and
you can be out here all day
but I think with the harassment from the
other Harrier Hawks
Ravens and other birds
it's keeping them a little bit active
so there's a lot of chases and stuff in
the sky really fun to photograph
um hard to record at times moving around
so much
if uh they're nice and low to the area
it's you get this really beautiful kind
of landscape shot
[Music]
[Laughter]
foreign
[Music]
Ed out and kind of hiding myself
here in this tall brush
one so that the wildlife the birds
flying over and stuff don't really get
too startled or spooked by me I kind of
blend in
uh but two uh just because there's other
birders and hikers and that sort of
thing and I don't really want to be in
their shot and be noticed so the camo
actually is more for humans than it is
for wildlife because let's face it they
know I'm here they could probably smell
me they could see me from I think Eagles
is like two miles away like
yeah it's pretty pretty crazy
foreign
[Music]
and I've counted so far I think five
short eared owls
it's it's hard to tell because
one will land and another one will take
off
so there's two or three out this way and
one or two over here
it's just incredible watching them hunt
all the
all the hairier Hawks
have uh
kind of disappeared there is one that
I've seen but
over the last three hours there hasn't
been a whole lot of activity there's
some herons that are still plucking
picking away at some uh fish and a few
other things
and that's it and then it was quiet for
two hours just sitting here freezing and
all of a sudden
one owl another owl they're all flying
around some of them are chasing one
another it's just been unreal I shot for
probably 30 minutes Non-Stop
from video back to
taking stills
I will say with the Nikon z9
um I haven't tried the A1 or the uh the
Canon R5 but
the autofocus is better with the
firmware up update I'm at the 3.0
firmware update
but it still hunts if the the subject
which in this case is the owl
isn't like
clearly visible for the camera to notice
and to hold on to it so
um I feel like Sony
and Canon have come so far with their
autofocus that I just hope Nikon can can
put up some new out updates
um but yeah so stoked to be out here
I'm glad I went with the uh the fluid
head
so that I can pan and move and and uh
and get some great video with any
jerking moving around
I'm photographing now at like
3200 of a shutter speed
I was at 2000 but the owls kept on
getting closer and closer and when I'm
moving back and forth and and panning
with them I just thought there was just
too much blur
too much motion that was happening not
just the owls that's moving I'm moving
there's some shaking because I'm excited
[Music]
foreign
here are some of the tips that I've
learned while being out photographing
the short-eared owls once I saw that
there were short-aired owls in the area
flying around I picked a location that
had the best backdrop composition
foreground elements and I just hunkered
down there's no sense in picking up and
moving to where the owls are flying to
and from because the the space isn't
that large and they're going to come
back fly around
there is also more than one short-eared
owl so your chances of waiting and
seeing one fly by you is at a higher
rate
and I noticed other photographers kind
of walking to and from and towards the
short-eared owls they would see them fly
back towards me so I'd see them hike all
the way back towards me it didn't make
any sense especially if you're carrying
around a tripod and all your heavy gear
pick the best composition best backdrop
best foreground and just wait so for me
I don't want to keep moving around
because the background kind of changes
the height of the grass there's that
popcorn kind of flowers that I wanted to
get in the foreground and some of the
images with the short-eared owls as they
hunt so that was very important for me
is the environment shots
I find the best settings for owl
photography is first and foremost your
shutter speed seems to be king to be
able to capture the birds in flight now
the shorter owls can move quite fast
especially when they're chasing one
another or they're being chased and so
I've I found that when they're far away
about 1600 of a second was a great
shutter speed I'm sure you can go slower
than that but since I'm moving there's
there's the tripod and and there could
be shaking from wind they're moving I I
figured 1600 was was slow as I wanted to
go and then if there were mid-range 2000
and then closer then it's 2500 so I
would just roll the shutter and go ahead
and hope that I got some shots now I was
out there for the whole day so I could
actually check to see if things were in
focus so that was good
um you know next would be my f-stop so I
was shooting with an F4 lens and I try
not to shoot It Wide Open one for it
being such a shallow depth of field
afraid of missing kind of focus but also
uh it's a little bit softer I think on
the extremes and shooting wide openness
a little softer so I didn't go any any
wider than 4.5
I think the highest in my my sweet spot
would be F 6.3 but sometimes you just
don't get the light that you need and
then my ISO I had it on auto ISO so
shutter was locked in my aperture I
moved here and there at times depending
on the lighting and then my ISO kind of
just filled in the blank
so that's my camera settings
um a big thing was a tripod I was blown
away by by people that other
photographers that came down with camera
equipment that they're hand holding now
I have a 200 500 here and my camera body
and and so I could hand hold that for a
bit but I feel like you're you're adding
to
movement and strain on the shoulders if
you're going to be shooting all day
tripod is like a must so if you like
this content and you want to see more of
it please subscribe give me the thumbs
up that always helps out and click that
notification Bell if you want to see
more videos like this
just hiking back I think I broke the mic
off of my camera
merry Merry Christmas
to you all right we need to put on some
Christmas music so you don't listen to
me sing